Duane Family Collection 1764-1933 Mss.SMs.Coll.2
American Philosophical Society
- Series III. Photographs & Prints, 1790 - 1890; 62 items
  - Engraving of Lord Eldon, ca 1840; 1 engraving; Wallis, H. (Henry), 1804-1890, engraver
  - Engraving of Convent Garden, ca 1840; 1 engraving; Unidentified
    4" x 6 1/2"
  - Engraving of fourth street, ca 1840; 1 engraving; Unidentified
    5 1/2" x 6 1/2"
  - Photograph of unidentified portrait, ca 1840; 1 photograph; Unidentified
    7 3/4" x 6"
  - Engraving of Benjamin Franklin, ca 1840; 1 engraving; Dodson, R. W. (Richard W.), 1812-1867., engraver, from a painting by J. B. Longacre after the portrait by G. Stuart
    9" x 6 1/2"
  - Engraving of unidentified man, ca 1840; 1 engraving; Unidentified
  - Engraving of David Rittenhouse, ca 1840; 1 engraving; Longacre, James Barton, 1794-1869, engraver, from a painting by Charles Wilson Peale
    8 1/2" x 6"
  - Engraving of Joseph Hopkinson, ca 1840; 1 engraving; Sartain, John, 1808-1897, engraver, from portrait by Thomas Sully
  - Engraving of Carpenter's Hall, ca 1840; 1 engraving; Unidentified
    3" x 5"
  - Engraving of Stephen Girard, ca 1840; 1 engraving; Unidentified
    8" x 5 1/4"
  - Engraving of Joseph Hopkinson, ca 1840; 1 engraving; Unidentified
  - Engraving of Andrew Jackson, ca 1840; 1 engraving; Longacre, James Barton, 1794-1869, engraver, drawn from life
  - Engraving of Henry Clay, ca 1840; 1 engraving; Sealey, A., engraver, from daguerreotype by Root
  - Engraving of John Quincy Adams, ca 1840; 1 engraving; Paradise, John Wesley, 1809-1862, engraver, from portrait by A. B. Durand
  - Drawing of William John Duane, ca 1840; 1 drawing; Unidentified
    3 1/2" x 2 1/4"
  - Engraving of unidentified man, 1843; 1 engraving; Unidentified
    Silhouette (outline) only.
    4" x 3 1/4"
  - Engraving of Georgina, Duchess of Devonshire, ca 1850; 1 engraving; Freeman, Samuel, 1773-1857, engraver, from original painting by Joshua Reynolds
  - Photograph of Katherine Duane Morgan, ca 1850; 1 photograph; Unidentified
    4" x 3 1/2"
  - Engraving of New York city, ca 1850; 1 engraving; Neagle, John B., ca. 1796-1866, engraver, from drawing by J. R. Smith
    7" x 8 1/2"
  - Photograph of Duane woman (unidentified), ca 1850; 1 photograph; Unidentified
    3 1/2" x 2 1/2"
  - Photograph of NW corner of Seventh and Arch, ca 1850; 1 photograph; Unidentified
    5 1/2" x 7"
  - Engraving of Louis McLane, ca 1850; 1 engraving; Kelly, Thomas, 1769-1855, engraver, from portrait by G. S. Newton
    8 1/2" x 6 1/4"
  - Photograph of the Bank of the United States, ca 1850; 1 photograph; Unidentified
    Girard's Bank.
    4" x 5"
  - Engraving of Amos Kendall, ca 1850; 1 engraving; Ritchie, Alexander Hay, 1822-1895, engraver
    9" x 6"
  - Engraving of Roger B. Taney, ca 1850; 1 engraving; Ritchie, Alexander Hay, 1822-1895, engraver
    8 1/2" x 5 1/2"
  - Photograph [of print] of Dr. Leib 1802, ca 1850; 1 photograph; Unidentified
    2 1/2" x 2 1/2"
  - Engraving of John C. Freemont, ca 1850; 1 engraving; Buttre, John Chester, 1821-1893, engraver
  - Photograph of William John Duane, ca 1860; 1 photograph; Unidentified
  - Photograph of William John? Duane, ca 1860; 1 photograph; Unidentified
    3 1/2" x 2 1/4" Seated, front side profile.
  - Engraving of George Mifflin Dallas, ca 1860; 1 engraving; Welch, Thomas B., 1814-1874., engraver, from daguerreotype by M. Clees and Germon
    9 3/4" x 6 1/2"
  - Engraving of Girard's Bank, ca 1860; 1 engraving; Unidentified
    Formerly Bank of the United States.
    8" x 10 1/2"
  - Photograph of Philadelphia, ca 1860; 1 photograph; Unidentified
    Wide angle; panorama.
  - Photograph of unidentified public building, ca 1860; 1 photograph; Unidentified
    Philadelphia?
  - Engraving of Thomas Jefferson, ca 1870; 1 engraving; Hall, Henry Bryan, 1808-1884, engraver from portrait by Gilbert Stuart
    8 1/2" x 6 1/2"
  - Engraving of Thomas P. Cope, ca 1870; 1 engraving; Sartain, John, 1808-1897, engraver, from portrait by J. Neagle
    8 1/2" x 5 3/4"
  - Photograph of building, ca 1870?; 1 photograph; Unidentified
    7 1/2" x 4 1/2"
  - Photograph of Philadelphia street, ca 1880?; 1 photograph; Unidentified
    William John Duane's residence, subsequent to 1842 untill death, on Locust Street, above sixteenth street.
    7" x 4 1/2"
  - Photograph of unidentified house, ca 1880?; 1 photograph; Unidentified
    Possible Philadelphia residence of William John Duane.
    7" x 4"
  - Photograph of unidentified house, ca 1880?; 1 photograph; Unidentified
    2 1/2" x 3 3/4"
  - Photograph of unidentified man, ca 1890; 1 photograph; Unidentified
    Bust.
    4" x 2 1/2"
  - Engraving of Benjamin Franklin, n.d.; 1 engraving; Smith, Hezekiah Wright, b. 1828, engraver from portrait in Versailles gallery
    12" 9 1/2." Accession 1974 1471ms.
  - Glass slides, n.d.; 94 glass slides; Unidentified
    Subjects relate to images of famous personages of the 18th and 19th centuries, images of Philadelphia locations, and images of selected manuscripts.
- Series IV. Memoir, 1764 - 1889; 51 items
  - Memoir of William John Duane, 1764 - 1889; 1 scrapbook; Unidentified
    Scrapbook including biographical information, prints and clippings.
- Series V. Maps, 1891-1892; 12 items
  - East & Little East rookeries, North rookery: St. George island, Bering Sea, Alaska, 1891; 1 pg.; U.S. Coast and Geodetic Survey.
    Charts J & H. Associated with Russell Duane as part of his appointment as Assistant Counsel for preparation of Case in matter submitted before the Bering Sea Board.
    Printed material: map. OS
  - Ketavie & Lukannon, Reef & Barbotch rookeries: Saint Paul island. Bering Sea, Alaska, 1891; 1 pg.; U.S. Coast and Geodetic Survey.
    Labled "Chart D." Associated with Russell Duane as part of his appointment as Assistant Counsel for preparation of Case in matter submitted before the Bering Sea Board of Arbitration.
  - Map showing positions of sealing vessels seized or warned by the government of the United States 1891, 1 pg.; U.S. Coast and Geodetic Survey.
    Associated with Russell Duane as part of his appointment as Assistant Counsel for preparation of Case in matter submitted before the Bering Sea Board of Arbitration.
  - Northeast Point rookery, St. Paul island. Bering Sea, Alaska, 1891; 1 pg.; U.S. Coast and Geodetic Survey.
  - Polavina rookery, St Paul island. Bering Sea, Alaska, 1891; 1 pg.; U.S. Coast and Geodetic Survey.
    Labled "Chart B." Associated with Russell Duane as part of his appointment as Assistant Counsel for preparation of Case in matter submitted before the Bering Sea Board of Arbitration.
  - Tolstoi and lagoon rookeries: St Paul Island. Bering Sea, Alaska, 1891; 1 pg.; U.S. Coast and Geodetic Survey.
    Labled "Chart E." Associated with Russell Duane as part of his appointment as Assistant Counsel for preparation of Case in matter submitted before the Bering Sea Board of Arbitration.
  - Zapadnie rookery and English Bay, St Paul island. Bering Sea, Alaska, 1891; 1 pg.; U.S. Coast and Geodetic Survey.
    Labled "Charts F & G." Associated with Russell Duane as part of his appointment as Assistant Counsel for preparation of Case in matter submitted before the Bering Sea Board of Arbitration.
  - Map of the Bering Sea and the North Pacific Ocean, 1892; 1 pg.; U.S. Coast and Geodetic Survey.
  - Map showing positions of sealing vessels seized or warned by the government of the United States during the seasons of 1886, 1887, 1889, 1892; 1 pg.; U.S. Coast and Geodetic Survey.
  - Migration chart showing the position of the Alaskan seal herd from January to July inclusive, 1892; 1 pg.; U.S. Coast and Geodetic Survey.
    Printed material: map. Unlocated as of January 8, 2008. OS
  - St. Paul and St George islands (Pribilof Group). Bering Sea, Alaska, 1892; 1 pg.; U.S. Coast and Geodetic Survey.
  - Sealing chart.Bering Sea and reported by United States vessels in 1891, 1892; 1 pg.; U.S. Coast and Geodetic Survey.